片名：伴我同行
克里斯多夫•钱伯斯律师 在餐厅被刺杀身亡
I was 12 going on 13 the first time I saw a dead human being.
我第一次看见死人 是在快要13岁那一年
It happened in the summer of 1959...
1959的夏天
...a long time ago...
以时间来算
...but only ifyou measure it in terms of years.
已经是陈年往事了
I was living in a small town in Oregon called Castle Rock.
我住在奥勒冈州一个叫凯斯罗的小镇
There were only 1,281 people, but to me it was the whole world.
人口只有1281人 但那是我的全世界
It"s the Bossman Bob Cormier. It"s a beautiful Friday morning in Portland.
我是大老板鲍伯•寇米耶 在波特兰市晴朗的星期五清晨
It"s 90 KLAM degrees and getting hotter.
这是KLAM电台 气温32度
Up the ladder with anotherplatter. It"s Bobby Day with Rockin' Robin...
金曲排行榜冠军是白金唱片 《摇滚罗宾》主唱人鲍比•戴
...it"s boss.
超酷的
How do you know a Frenchman's been in your backyard?
如何知道法国佬来过你家后院？
I'm French, okay.
我是法国人耶
Your garbage cans are empty and your dog's pregnant.
你的垃圾桶被挖空 你家的狗怀孕
Didn't I just say I was French?
我不是说过我是法国人了吗？
-I knock. -Shit.
- 摊牌 - 妈的
Twenty-nine.
Twenty-two.
Piss up a rope.
去死啦
Gordie's out, Ol' Gordie just bit the bag and stepped out the door.
高弟出局了 输牌被踢出门了
Come on, man, deal.
快发牌
Teddy Duchamp was the craziest guy we hung around with.
泰迪•杜相是我们朋友中最疯狂的人
He didn"t have much of a chance in life.
他的人生很倒霉
His dad was given to fits of rage.
他老爸很容易暴怒
One time he held Teddy"s ear to a stove and almost burned it off.
有一次他揪着泰迪的耳朵 用炉火烫到它差点掉了
I knock.
摊牌
You four-eyed pile of shit.
你这个死四眼田鸡
The "pile of shit" has 1,000 eyes.
我是千里眼
What?
什么？
What's so funny? I got thirty, what have you got?
有什么好笑？我的牌是30 你的是什么？
Sixteen.
Go ahead, keep laughing.
好呀 继续笑啊
You're down to your ride, pal.
你赌注只剩下一台破铁马了
Chris Chambers was the leader of our gang and my best friend.
克里斯•钱伯斯是团体的头头 也是我最好的朋友
He came from a bad family and everyonejust knew he"d turn out bad.
他的家庭很坏 所以大家都知道他会变坏
Including Chris.
包括克里斯自己
That's not the secret knock.
敲错暗号了
I forgot the secret knock. Let me in.
我忘记暗号了 让我进去
Vern.
维恩
Come on, you guys, open up.
拜托啦 帮我开门
Man, you guys are not going to believe this. This is so boss.
天啊 你们一定不会相信的 这太酷了
Wait till you hear this.
你们听听看这个事情
You won't believe it. It's unbelievable.
绝对不会相信 太不可思议了
Let me catch my breath. I ran all the way from my house.
让我喘口气 我从我家跑来这里
"I ran all the way home"
我跑回家里
Come on. Listen to me, this is boss.
别闹了 听我说 因为太酷了
"Just to say I'm sorry"
就为了说声抱歉
Okay, forget it. I don't have to tell you nothin'.
算了 我才不需要跟你们讲
Hold on, you guys. Hold on. What is it, man?
等一下 等等 兄弟 怎么了？
Great, you won't believe this, sincerely.
好 你们绝对不会相信的
"I ran all the way home"
我跑回家里
Screw you guys. Forget it.
去你们的 算了
What is it?
到底什么事？
Can you camp out tonight?
你们今晚能外宿吗？
I mean, if you tell your folks we're gonna tent out in my backfield?
就跟你们爸妈说 来我家后院露营？
I think so.
应该可以
Except my dad's kind of on a mean streak. He's been drinking a lot lately.
但我爸最近脾气很差 常常喝很多酒
You got to. Sincerely, you won't believe this. Can you, Gordie?
一定要出来 真的 你们不会相信的 你能吗？高弟
Yeah, probably.
也许吧
So what are you pissing and moaning about Vern?
你在大呼小叫个什么劲 维恩？
-I knock. -What?
- 摊牌 - 什么？
You liar! You ain't got no pat hand.
骗子! 你根本没好牌
You didn't deal yourself no pat hand.
你发的根本都是烂牌
Make your draw, shitheap.
赶快抽牌 白痴
You guys want to go see a dead body?
你们想看死人的尸体吗？
I was under the porch digging, you know?
我在我家门口底下挖土
We all understood what Vern meant right away.
我们马上都明白维恩的意思
At the beginning of the school year he had buried ajar ofpennies...
今年开学的时候 他在他家地底下
...underneath his house.
埋了一罐零钱
He drew a treasure map so he could find them again.
画了一张藏宝图以便日后再挖出来
A week later his mom cleaned out his room and threw away the map.
一个星期后 他妈妈在整理房间时 把他的藏宝图丢掉了
Vern had been trying to find those pennies for nine months...
维恩连续九个月都在挖他的零钱罐
...nine months, man.
九个月耶
You didn't know whetherlaugh or cry.
真是令人啼笑皆非
Jesus, Billy, we gotta do something.
我的天啊 比利 不能就这样算了
Why? Who cares?
为什么？有什么关系？
-We saw him. -So?
- 我们是目击证人 - 又怎样？
It's nothin' to us. The kid's dead so it's nothin' to him, neither.
对我们来说没差 那小孩已经死了 对他也没差
And who gives a shit if they ever find him? I don't.
谁在乎他们找不找得到他？我才不管
It's that kid they're talking about on the radio.
但那小孩就是电台一直报导的那个
Brocker or Brower or Flowers, whatever his name is.
布洛克 布洛尔还是弗莱尔什么的
The train must have hit him.
他一定是被火车撞死的
Big fucking deal.
有什么了不起的
We had all followed the Ray Browerstory closely...
雷•布洛尔是当时我们都很关心的新闻
...since he was a kid our age.
因为他跟我们年龄相当
Three days before, he left to pick blueberries and nobody'd seen him since.
三天前 他出门采蓝莓 就再也没人见过他了
I think we should tell the cops.
我想我们应该报警
You don't go squawking to the cops after you boosted a car.
你偷车以后还去报警喔 白痴
They'll want to know how we got way out on Back Harlow Road.
他们一定会问 我们怎么回到后哈洛路上的
They know we don't got no car.
因为他们知道我们没车
It's best we just keep quiet, then they can't touch us.
我们最好都闭嘴 他们就拿我们没辙
But we could make an anonymous call.
我们可以匿名报警
They trace those calls stupid. I seen it on Highway Patrol and on Dragnet.
他们会追踪号码 笨蛋 你没看过电视剧吗？
Yeah, right.
对
I wish we never boosted that goddamned Dodge.
我真希望我们没偷那辆该死的车
I wish Ace had been with us.
真希望老大也在
-We could've said he was in his car. -He wasn't!
- 就可以跟条子说我们坐他的车 - 他不在
-Are we gonna tell him? -We're not going to tell nobody.
- 要告诉老大吗？ - 谁都别说
Nobody, never. You dig me?
到死都不能说 知道吗？
I know the Back Harlow Road.
我知道后哈洛路在哪里
It comes to a dead end by the Royal River. The train tracks are right there.
它走到底就是皇家河旁边 铁轨就在那里
Me and my dad fished out there.
我和我爸常去那里钓鱼
If they had known you were under there, they would've killed you.
老天啊 他们要是知道你在阳台底下 一定打死你
Could he have gotten all the way from Chamberlain to Harlow? That's really far.
他有可能从香柏蓝走到哈洛路吗？ 很远耶
Sure. He probably started walking on the tracks and followed them the whole way.
一直走到底 当然 他应该是顺着铁轨走
Yeah, right.
对 对
And then after dark, a train must have come along and "el smako."
然后天一黑 有一辆火车就 冲撞上去
I bet you, if we find him, we'll get our pictures in the paper.
我打赌要是我们找到他 一定会上报纸
We could even be on TV.
对 还可以上电视
-Sure. -We'll be heroes.
- 当然 - 我们就成了英雄
I don't know. Billy will know I found out.
不一定 比利会知道被我发现了
He's not going to care. 'Cause it's gonna be us that find him.
他才不会管 因为是我们找到尸体的
Not Billy and Charlie Hogan, and the boosted the car.
不是比利和查理•荷根 还有偷来的车
They'll probably pin a medal on you.
他们也许还会颁发奖章给你 维恩
You think so?
你说真的吗？
Sure.
当然
What'll we tell our folks?
要怎么跟爸妈讲？
Exactly what you said.
就你刚才说的
We'll tell our folks that we're tenting in your backfield.
我们跟爸妈讲要去你家后院露营
You tell your folks your sleeping at Teddy's.
你告诉你爸妈 我们要去泰迪家过夜
Then we say we're going to the drag races the next day.
然后我们就说隔天要去看赛车
We're rock solid until dinner tomorrow night.
这样就有足足到明天晚餐的时间
Man that's a plan and a half.
真是好计划
But, if we find the body in South Harlow,
但假如我们在南哈洛找到那小孩的尸体
they'll know we didn't go to the races.
大家就会知道我们没去看赛车
We'll get hided.
我们会被打
Nobody will care...
没有人会在乎的
...because everybody will be jazzed at our discovery...
大家都会因为我们找到人而兴奋
...it won't make a difference.
根本没差
My dad will hide me anyway, but it's worth it.
我爸一定会揍我 但管他的 很值得
-Shit, yeah. -Let's do it. What do you say?
- 对 - 就这样做吧 大家同意吗？
-All right. -Gordie?
- 好 - 高弟？
Sure.
当然好
Vern?
维恩？
I don't know.
我不知道
Come on, Vern.
拜托 维恩
-Okay. -All right.
- 好吧 - 太好了
Too cool. Very cool.
太酷 太棒了! 太棒了! 耶!
I wanted to share my friends' enthusiasm, but I couldn't.
我很想分享朋友的兴奋 但我做不到
Thatsummer at home, I had become The lnvisible Boy.
因为那年夏天 我在家里成了隐形人
Mom, do you know where my canteen is?
妈 你知道我的水壶放在哪吗？
Mom?
妈？
It's in Denny's room.
在丹尼的房间
In April, my older brother, Dennis, had been killed in a jeep accident.
四月的时候 我哥哥丹尼 因吉普车车祸身亡
Four months had passed...
四个月过去了
...but my parents still hadn't been able to put the pieces back together again.
我爸妈还是一直无法走出伤痛
凯斯罗高中
密西根州立大学
Gordie, I gotsomething for you.
高弟 我有东西给你
This, my friend, is for you.
这是我要送你的
-This is your Yankee cap. -No.
- 但是丹尼 这是你的洋基队球帽 - 不
This is your Yankee cap.
现在是你的了
It's a good luck cap. Know how many fish we'll catch?
这是顶幸运帽 你知道戴着它会钓到多少鱼吗？
-How much? -A bazillion.
- 多少？ - 无限多
A bazillion fish. It looks good on you, too. Just like that.
无限多的鱼 而且你戴起来很好看 像这样
-No. I'm going blind. -Don't start with me. Give me a hug.
- 老莫 我看不见了 - 别闹了 小刺猬 来 大哥抱一下
You found it.
找到啦
找到了
Why can't you have friends like Denny's?
你交的朋友怎么不像丹尼的朋友
Dad, they're okay.
爸 他们很好
Sure they are. A thief and two feebs.
是很好 一个小偷加两个怪咖
Chris isn't a thief.
克里斯不是小偷
He stole the milk money at school.
他在学校偷了牛奶钱
He's a thief in my book.
在我看来他就是小偷
It was almost noon as we set out to find the body of a dead kid named Ray Brower.
我们准备出发找雷布洛尔的尸体时 已经快要中午了
Right here's cool.
到这里就好
-Thanks a lot. -Sure thing.
- 谢了 - 不客气
-You want to see something? -What?
- 想不想看个好东西？ - 当然
-You okay? -I'm fine.
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
What is it?
是什么？
-You've got to see this. -What is it?
- 你一定要看看 - 什么东西？
What is it?
到底是什么？
You want to be the Lone Ranger or the Cisco Kid?
你想当警长还是盗贼？
Walking, talking Jesus!
我的老天啊!
-Where'd you get this? -Hocked it from my old man's bureau.
- 你在哪拿到的？ - 从我爸的书房偷的
It's a .45.
这是点45的手枪
I can see that.
看得出来
- You got shells for it?   - Yeah.
- 有子弹吗？ - 有
I took what was left in the box.
我拿了盒子里全部的子弹
My dad'll think he used them himself shooting at beer cans while he was drunk.
我爸一定会以为是他自己喝醉酒 拿去射啤酒罐
-Is it loaded? -Hello, no. What do you think I am?
- 装了子弹吗？ - 没有 你以为我是谁？
Jesus!
天啊!
Let's get out of here. Come on.
快跑! 快点!
Gordie did it. Gordon Lachance is shooting up Castle Rock.
是高弟弄的! 高弟•拉强斯要射凯斯罗!
Shut up.
闭嘴!
Hey, who did that? Who's letting cherry bombs off out here?
是谁？谁在外面乱放鞭炮？
You should have seen your face. Damn, that was cool!
天啊 你该看看你的表情 真是太酷了!
-That was really fine. -You knew it was loaded, you wet end!
- 真好玩 - 你明明知道装了子弹 白痴!
I'm in trouble now. That Tupper babe saw me.
我闯祸了 被那个欧巴桑看到了
-Shit, she thought it was firecrackers. -I don't care. It was a mean trick.
- 高弟 她以为那是放鞭炮 - 我不管 克里斯 这玩笑很烂
I didn't know it was loaded.
我不知道里面有子弹
-Honest. -You swear?
- 真的 - 你发誓？
I swear.
对 我发誓
On your mother's name?
用你妈妈的名字发誓？
Even if she goes to hell for your lie?
假如你说谎 她就要下地狱
I swear.
好 我发誓
Pinky swear?
勾手指？
Pinky swear.
勾手指
Girls, where you going?
小姑娘们 你们在干嘛？
-Come on, my brother gave me that! -And now you're giving it to me.
- 喂 别这样 那是我哥送的! - 现在送给我啦
Give it to me!
还给我
That's mine.
那是我的!
You're a real asshole, you know that?
你真的是混蛋 你知道吗？
Your brother's not very polite, Eyeball.
你的弟弟不太有礼貌 眼球
Now, Christopher.
克里斯多夫
I know you didn't mean to insult my friend.
我知道你不是故意骂我朋友的
I know he didn't mean to insult me.
我知道他不是故意的
That's why I'll give him the opportunity to take it back.
所以我给他一次机会认错
-Shit. -Take it back, kid.
- 该死 - 快认错 小鬼
-Stop it, you're hurting him. -You bastard! Let go, man.
- 拜托 别这样 你弄痛他了 - 你这混蛋! 放开我
-Stop it! Cut it out! -Take it back, kid.
- 住手! 别这样!  - 快认错 小鬼
You big... Okay, I take it back.
你这大混…好啦 我收回 我认错
There.
这才乖
Now I feel a whole lot better about this.
我心情好多了
How about you?
你呢？
Good.
很好
See you later girls.
再见了 小娘儿们
Let's just forget them.
走吧 别理他们
What do we need a pistol for anyway?
我们需要带枪干嘛？
It's spooky sleeping out at night in the woods. You might see a bear.
晚上森林里是很恐怖的 也许会遇到熊
Or a garbage can.
或是垃圾桶
I brought a comb.
我带了梳子
What do we need a comb for?
带梳子干嘛？
If we get on TV we want to look good, don't we?
要上电视当然要帅呀
-That's a lot of thinking, Vern. -Thanks.
- 考虑得真周到 维恩 - 谢谢
Two for flinching.
缩一下被打两下
How far do you think it's gonna be?
你认为路途有多远？
If we follow the tracks all the way into Harlow, it should be about 20 miles.
假如沿着铁轨一直走到哈洛 应该有20几公里
Sound about right to you?
差不多吧 高弟你说呢？
It might even be 30.
应该是 说不定快30公里
Maybe we should just hitchhike.
我们也许应该搭便车
-No way, that sucks. -Why not?
- 不行 那太瞎了 - 有何不可？
We could go out to Route 7 to the Shiloh church...
在七号公路下车到示罗教堂
...then down the Back Harlow Road. We'll be there by sundown.
然后往回走到后哈洛路 天黑以前就会到了
That's pussy.
那太娘了
It's a long way.
喂 路途很远耶
Did your mother ever have any kids that lived?
你妈妈生的小孩 还有没有人活着？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
We have to fill up at the junkyard. My dad said it was a safe well.
我们要在垃圾场加水 我爸说那口井可以用
-Not if Chopper's there. -If he's there we'll send you in.
- 假如恰波在就惨了 - 恰波在的话就派你去
Ha Ha. Very funny.
哈哈 不好笑
I'm kind of hungry. Who's got the food?
我有点饿了 谁带了食物？
Did anybody bring anything?
完蛋了! 有人带食物吗？
Not me. Gordie?
我没有 高弟呢？
This is great. What are we supposed to do? Eat our feet?
太好了 我们该怎么办？吃自己的肉吗？
You mean, you didn't bring anything, either?
你是说 你也什么都没带？
This wasn't my idea. It was Vern's. Why didn't you bring something?
这不是我的主意 是维恩的 你怎么没带东西来吃？
I have to think of everything? I brought the comb.
你要我怎样？负责所有的事吗？ 我带了梳子呀
What do you need a comb for? You don't have any hair.
你带梳子干嘛？又没什么头发
I brought it for you guys, so you'd have a comb.
我为你们大家带的 等我们到的时候…
Let's see how much money we've got?
来看看我们带了多少钱吧？
I got $1.02.
我有一块两分钱
And 68 cents from Chris.
我有68分钱
60 cents from Teddy.
泰迪有60分钱
7 cents, Vern?
维恩 你才7分钱？
I haven't found my pennies yet.
我还没挖到我的零钱罐呀
$2.37 cents, not bad.
两块三毛七 还不赖
Quidaciolu's is at the end of the road by the junkyard.
杂货店就在垃圾场旁边的小路上
I think we can get some stuff there.
我们可以去那里买东西
Train coming.
火车要来了
Geronimo!
印第安酋长!
Come on, Teddy.
- 过来呀 泰迪 - 不
I'm gonna dodge it.
我会闪过火车的
Get off the tracks. You're crazy.
快过来 别站在铁轨上 你疯了
Train dodge. Dig it?
闪火车 懂吗？
Get the hell off the tracks. You want to get yourself killed?
快下来 泰迪 你想被撞死吗？
Just like the beach at Normandy.
就像登陆诺曼底一样
Don't tell me what to do or I'll kill you.
别命令我该怎么做 不然我就杀死你
I'm trying to save your life.
我只是想救你
You want to kill yourself?
你想自杀吗？
Is that what you want, goddamn it?
该死 这就是你想要的？
You tried to kill yourself.
你想自杀
I don't need no babysitter.
我不需要保姆
You do, too.
你需要
Skin it.
答应我
I could have dodged it.
我可以闪得过的
Listen, you can dodge it on the way back.
泰迪 你回来的路上再证明吧
Peace.
和解
Skin it.
答应我
罗斯兰宅 甜蜜的家 - 88114
About this time, Charlie and Billy were playing mailbox baseball...
在这个同时 查理和比利 跟老大和眼球
...with Ace and Eyeball.
正在玩信箱棒球游戏
Shit on that. Goddamn it!
妈的 该死!
Shouldn't have gone for a wooden one.
不应该选木制的信箱
Why don't you tell me something I don't know, asshole?
你有我不知道的事情要报告吗 混帐？
Billy, you're up.
比利 该你说了
You guys win. I don't want to play no more.
你们赢了 我不想再玩了
You can't quit.
你不能弃权
We only played three innings. That'd be a non-official game.
我们才玩了三局 这根本不算正式的比赛
Ace, me and....
老大 我和…
What's with you homos? You've been acting psycho all day.
你们两个娘儿们在搞什么？整天都疯疯的
What is it?
怎么了？
It's nothing, right?
没事 没什么事 对吧？
Then if you don't mind, I'd like to finish this game...
你们不介意的话 我想在领老人年金以前
...before I start collecting my social security, okay?
结束这场比赛 好吗？
You're up, Billy. Move it.
换你了 比利 动作快
All right, give me this fucking stick.
好 给我棒子
Let's play ball.
开始打球
Foul ball.
出界
禁止穿越 - 请勿入内
Vern, it looks like your mom's been out driving again.
维恩 看来你妈妈又在外面开车了
That's so funny I forgot to laugh.
真好笑 我都忘了笑
Stand back, men!
往后退!
Paratroopers, over the side!
伞兵 往旁边站!
"No Trespassing" was enforced by Milo Pressman, thejunkman...
"禁止穿越"是垃圾场管理员麦罗•普里斯曼和他养的狗恰波
...and his dog, Chopper.
一起捍卫的规定
The most feared and leastseen dog in Castle Rock.
恰波是凯斯罗众所皆知和最害怕的狗
Legend had it that Milo had trained Chopper notjust to sic...
有传言说 麦罗不只训练恰波攻击人
...but to sic specific parts of the human anatomy.
而且还专攻人体的某部位
Thus, a kid who had illegally scaled thejunkyard fence...
因此 只要有小孩非法越入垃圾场的栅栏
...might hear the dread cry: "Chopper, sic balls!"
他就会听到有人大喊 "恰波 攻击蛋蛋! "
But right now neither the dread Chopper nor Milo...
但现在眼前既看不见恰波
...was anywhere in sight.
也不见麦罗
Teddy's crazy.
泰迪疯了
Come on, men, move it out!
B.A.R．在哪里？快点过来 兄弟们!
He won't live to be 20, I bet.
我猜他应该活不过20岁
Remember the time you saved him in the tree?
还记得有一次你从树上救他下来吗？
I dream about that sometimes.
我有时候会梦到这些事
Except in the dream I miss him. I just get a few hairs and down he goes.
但在梦里我总是没救到他 只抓到他的几根头发 他就掉下去了
It's weird.
很奇怪
That is weird.
对 很奇怪
But you didn't miss him.
但你救到他了
Chris Chambers never misses, does he?
克里斯•钱伯斯从不失手 对吧？
Not even when the ladies leave the seat down.
尤其是对准马桶尿尿的时候
Race you.
我们来赛跑
-No, I don't think so. -Over to the pump.
- 我不想 - 跑到帮浦那边 快点
-I'm kind of tired. Go. -You're a dead man, Lachance!
- 我有点累 快跑  - 你死定了 拉强斯
It looks like Lachance has got him this time.
看来拉强斯好像快赢了
He's got Chambers beat.
他打败了钱伯斯
But what's this? Chambers is making his move.
但这怎么回事？钱伯斯开始动作了
Lachance is fading and it's Chambers at the tape.
拉强斯落后了 钱伯斯逼近终点线
The crowd goes wild.
观众热烈掌声
You guys been watching The Mickey Mouse Club lately?
你们最近看了《米奇老鼠俱乐部》吗？
I think Annette's tits are getting bigger.
安妮特的咪咪越来越大了
-You think so? -I think so.
- 真的吗？ - 对呀
I think he's right.
我也同意
I've been noticing that the A and the E are starting to bend around the sides.
我看到她衣服上的字母越撑越大了
Annette's tits are great.
安妮特的咪咪好美喔
This is a really good time.
这真是太好玩了
The most.
美好的时光
A blast.
太棒了
Vern didn"tjust mean being offlimits inside thejunkyard...
维恩所指的不只是我们在垃圾场里 毫不忌讳的放肆
...or fudging on our folks...
或是对父母撒谎的事
...or going on a hike up the tracks to Harlow. He meant those things, but...
或者沿着铁轨走到哈洛的事 当然这些都很棒
...itseems to me now it was more and that we all knew it.
但我们都心知肚明 还有更多的大事要发生
Everything was there and around us.
我们都蓄势待发
We knew exactly who we were and exactly where we were going.
完全清楚自己身在何处 并且接下来要去哪里
It was grand.
真是太棒了
Great, spit at the fat kid. Real good.
很好 对胖小子喷水 真有你的
What time is it?
几点了 高弟？
It's a quarter after one.
1点15分
You'd better go get the food. Junkyard opens at 3:00.
我们最好去买东西吃 垃圾场三点开门
Chopper'll be here.
恰波会在那里
Sic balls.
攻击蛋蛋
You go. You can pick us up on the way back.
你去 在回来的路上来接我们
I'm not going alone. We should all go.
我才不要自己去 大家一起去
-I'm staying right here. -I'm not going.
- 我留下来 - 对 我才不去
Girls, cool it. We'll flip for it.
娘儿们 冷静点 我们来丢铜板
Okay.
好
Odd man goes.
不一样的人去
That's you, Gordie, odd as a cod.
就是你 高弟 你最不一样
Flip or eat lead.
丢铜板决胜负
Four tails.
四个反面
Jesus, man, that's a goocher.
天啊 这是个不好的预兆
-That doesn't mean anything. -No, let's go again.
- 这根本不算什么 - 不 再丢一次
That's really bad.
非常不好
Remember Clint Bracken and those guys got wiped out on Weed Hill in Durham?
你还记得克林特•布莱肯那群人在杜汉的杂草丘被杀光的事吗？
He said they flipped for beers and they came up with a goocher...
比利告诉我他们丢铜板决定谁去买啤酒
...just before they got in the car.
结果在上车前丢出了一样的坏预兆
And, bang! They all got totalled.
然后 碰! 人车全毁
I don't like this. Sincerely.
我真的不喜欢这种事情
Nobody believes that crap about moons and goochers.
维恩 没有人相信这种迷信的事
It's baby stuff. Now come on, flip again.
那是骗小孩的 快丢铜板
Are you going to flip or not?
你要丢还是不丢？
We don't have all day.
快点 维恩 时间不多了
You lose, Gordie.
你输了 高弟
Gordie loses.
高弟输了
Old Gordie just screwed the pooch.
高弟输惨了
Does the word "retarded" mean anything to you?
"白痴"这个字你听得懂吗？
Go get the provisions, you morphadite.
高弟 你这个阴阳人 还不快去买食物
Don't call me any of your mother's pet names.
别用你妈妈的小名叫我
What a wet end you are, Lachance.
你真是个笨蛋 拉强斯
Shut up.
闭嘴
I don't shut up, I grow up. And when I look at you, I throw up.
我才不闭嘴 等我长大 我看着你吐满地
Then your mother goes around the corner and she licks it up.
然后你妈妈就会去把呕吐物舔光
Finding new and disgusting ways to degrade a friend"s mother...
当时非常流行寻找新的方法
...was always held as high regard.
来侮辱你朋友的妈妈
Ain't you Denny Lachance's brother?
你不是丹尼•拉强斯的弟弟吗？
Yes, sir.
是
Shame what happened to him.
他发生了那样的事真遗憾
The Bible says, "In the midst of life we are in death."
圣经说: "死亡随时可能在我们生命中发生"
Did you know that?
你知道吗？
I lost a brother in Korea.
我有个兄弟在韩战死了
You look like your brother Denny.
你长得很像你哥哥丹尼
People ever tell you that?
有人这样说过吗？
Sometimes.
偶尔
I remember the year he was All-Conference.
我还记得他是足球联盟的明星球员
Quarterback, he played.
他担任四分卫
Boy, could he throw.
投球真不是盖的
Father God and Sonny Jesus.
我的老天啊
Could be some scouts at the game tomorrow.
明天比赛场上也许会有星探
-I don't know, Pop. -Dad, could I have the potatoes?
- 不知道 爸 - 爸 我要吃马铃薯
-That's what I hear, Son. -Are you going to see Jane after the game?
- 我听说了 儿子 - 你比赛完会去找珍妮吗？
I think she's a lovely girl.
她是个好女孩
-Dad, may I please have the potatoes? -Dorothy, don't talk to the boy about girls.
- 爸 请把马铃薯传过来 好吗？ - 桃乐丝 别跟他说女生的事
He shouldn't be thinking about girls. This is the biggest game of his life.
人生最重要的赛事 当前他不应该去想女孩子的事
-Dennis, when you're there tomorrow-- -Did you read the story Gordie wrote?
- 丹尼 你明天上场的时候… - 爸 你读过高弟写的作文了吗？
Gordie wrote a story.
高弟写了一个故事
-It was really good. -What did you write, sweetheart?
- 真的写得很好 - 甜心 你写了什么？
That's what I'm talking about. Football takes concentration.
你看 我就说嘛 打足球要专心
You start in on the girls and his mind's all over the place.
都是你跟他说女生的事 害他脑袋都不专心了
I really liked it.
高弟 我很喜欢你的故事
I thought it was great.
很好看
You play football?
你踢足球吗？
Do you play football?
No.
不打
What do you do?
你会做什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
Your brother, Denny, sure could play football.
你哥哥丹尼足球踢得真好
There you go, kid. $1.50 of hamburger.
来 孩子 汉堡一共是一块半
You, kid! What are you doing there! Come over here!
你这小鬼! 在那里做什么？ 快给我过来!
You, come back here, goddamn it! I'll sic my dog on you.
小鬼 回来这里 该死!  我叫我的狗攻击你
Run! Gordie, run!
跑 高弟! 快跑!
Chopper, sic him! Sic him, boy!
恰波 攻击他 攻击!
Now he said: "Sic him, boy."
他说: "恰波 攻击他"
But what I heard was: "Chopper, sic balls."
我听到的是: "恰波 攻击蛋蛋"
That's Chopper?
那就是恰波？
Chopper was my firstlesson in the vast difference between myth and reality.
恰波是我人生第一次学到传说和事实是有差距的
Come on, Choppie. Kiss my ass, Choppie.
来呀 恰波 亲我的屁屁 恰波 来呀
Come on, bite shit.
来呀 咬我的便便
Sic balls, Choppie.
快呀 攻击蛋蛋 恰波
You kids stop teasing that dog! You hear me? Stop teasing him!
你们别再取笑那只狗了 听到没 不准笑它
Sonny, I'm gonna beat your ass, teasing my dog like that!
死小鬼 你们敢笑我的狗 看我不打得你屁股开花
Let's see you climb over this fence and get me, fat ass!
好呀 我看你这大胖子怎么爬得过栅栏来打我
Don't you call me that!
你敢叫我大胖子
You little tin weasel peckerwood loony's son!
你这小混蛋 神经病的儿子
What did you call me?
你说什么？
I know who you are, you're Teddy Duchamp.
我知道你是谁 你是泰迪•杜相
Your dad's a loony.
你爸是个神经病
A loony up in the nuthouse at Togus.
住在托格斯疯人院里面
He took your ear and he put it to a stove and he burnt it off.
他抓着你的耳朵用炉火烫到都掉了
My father stormed the beach at Normandy.
我爸是登陆诺曼底的英雄
He's crazier than a shithouse rat. No wonder you're acting the way you are...
他是个不折不扣的疯子 难怪老鼠生的儿子会打洞
...with a loony for a father.
有其父必有其子
You call my dad a loony again and I'll kill you.
你再骂我爸疯子 我就杀了你
Loony, loony.
疯子 疯子
I'm gonna rip your head off and shit down your neck.
我要扯掉你的头 然后在你身上拉屎
No, I'm gonna kill him!
不 我要杀了他
You come on and try it, you little bastard.
来呀 试试看呀 你这没礼貌的小杂种
He wants you to go over so he can beat you up then take you to the cops.
然后带你去警察局 他要你过来让他打得剉屎
You watch your mouth. Let him do his own fighting.
你嘴巴放干净 少鸡婆 让他自己处理
Sure, you only outweigh him by 500 pounds, fat ass.
对 你只比他重两百公斤而已 大胖子
I know your name.
我知道你的名字
You're Lachance. I know all you guys.
你是拉强斯 我认识你们全部的人
And your fathers will get a call from me.
你们家长今天会接到我的电话
Except for the loony up in Togus.
除了在托格斯的那个神经病以外
I'm going to kill you. I'll show you.
- 好了 - 我要杀了你
-Get him away from... -You foulmouthed whoremaster.
- 把他拉开 - 你这个满嘴脏话的小杂种
You son of a bitch!
你这混蛋
You come back here.
你给我回来
Do you hear me?
回来 听到没？
- Nobody ranks out my old man.   - Come back here!
- 没有人可以骂我老爸 - 回来
-My father stormed the beach... -I said, "Come back here!"
- 我爸是登陆诺曼底的英雄 - 我叫你回来
- He stormed the beach, you faggot!   - Come back here.
- 他是登陆诺曼底的英雄 你这娘炮  - 给我回来
We showed him. Thought we were a bunch of pussies.
我们给他好看了 他还以为我们是娘们
He ranked my old man.
他侮辱我老爸
I wondered how he could care so much for his dad who'd almost killed him...
我不明白为何泰迪这么在乎一个差点杀了他的老爸
...and I didn't care about my own who hadn't touched me since I was three.
从我三岁喝了洗手台下的漂白水以来
That was for eating bleach under the sink.
我一点也不在乎我那个就再也没打过我的爸爸
He ranked my old man.
他侮辱我老爸
What do you care what a fat old pile of shit like him says about your dad?
你干嘛管那个大肥猪说你爸什么？
He still stormed the beach at Normandy, right?
他是登陆诺曼底的英雄 对吧？
Do you think that pile of shit was at Normandy?
你认为那个大肥猪有没有去诺曼底打仗？
Forget it, okay?
算了 好吗？
He knows nothin' about your old man. He's shit.
他根本不懂你爸 他只是个狗屎
Whatever's between you and your old man, he can't change that.
你跟你爸之间的感情 是他不能改变的
Forget it, all right?
算了 好吗？别再说了
I'm sorry if I'm spoiling everybody's good time.
很抱歉我害大家不开心
It's okay.
没关系 算了
I'm not sure it should be a good time.
我不确定我们会开心
-You saying you want to go back? -No.
- 你是说你想回家吗？ - 不
But going to see a dead kid, maybe it shouldn't be a party.
但去看一个小孩的尸体 应该不是什么好事
If he's really bad, like all cut up with blood and shit all over him...
假如他死得很惨 血肉模糊之类的
...l might have nightmares.
我可能会做恶梦
All guts and eyeballs ready to jump and grab...
肠子眼球都掉出来 然后随时都会跳起来抓人…
Shut up, goddamn it!
闭嘴 维恩
I can't help it.
我没办法不去想
Sorry.
抱歉
It was only a quarter to three, butit felt much later.
当时是下午2点45分了 但感觉已经很晚了
It was too hot and too much had happened.
天气太热 又有太多事情发生了
We weren"t even close to the Royal River.
我们根本离皇家河还很远
We needed to get moving if we were going to make some real miles before dark.
假如想在天黑前尽量赶路的话 我们必须快点行动
眼镜蛇
Hold still, will you?
别乱动 好吗？
So what's with you and this Connie Palermo chick?
你跟康妮•帕勒莫那个妞怎么样了？
I've been seeing her for over a month, and all she'll let me do is feel her tits.
我们交往一个多月了 她只让我摸她咪咪
She's a Catholic. They're all like that.
她是天主教徒 她们都这样
You want to get laid you gotta get yourself a Protestant.
你想上床的话 就要找新教徒
A Jew's good.
或是犹太人
A KLAM newsbreak.
KLAM新闻快报
We interrupt to bring you an update on the search for...
插播一段搜寻12岁男孩
...12 year-old Ray Brower.
雷•布洛尔的最新消息
The police have expanded theirsearch to Mutton...
警方已经将搜寻范围扩大到莫顿
...Durham and the outlying areas.
杜汉和郊区
When are they going to give up?
妈的 他们什么时候才要放弃？
The kid's gone. They'll never find him.
那孩子死了 他们找不到的
Not where they're looking.
他们找的范围错了
I was right, they ain't never gonna find him.
我说的对 查理 他们永远找不到的
Would you hold still? You're making me fuck up the snake part.
你别动好吗？你害我蛇都画歪了
I'll tell you how they're gonna find him.
我告诉你他们要怎么找到他
Ten years from now a hunter's going to go into the woods to take a leak...
十年后 有个猎人去森林尿尿
...wind up pissing on his bones.
结果尿在他的骨头上
I bet you a $1,000 they find him before that.
我赌一千块他们会很快找到
Bet you $2,000 they don't.
我赌两千他们不会
-Well, asshole...   -What's the big deal?
- 白痴… - 这有什么大不了？
- Who cares?  - Would you two just shut the fuck up.
- 谁在乎？ - 你们两个闭嘴
If either one of you assholes had $2,000, I'd kill you both.
假如你们有两千块 我早就干掉你们了
We"re back here with The Bossman.
再度回到大老板鲍伯•寇米耶的节目
From the racks and stacks, it"s the best on wax.
男女老少 东南西北
It"s the Cordettes, with Lollipop.
欢迎收听美女声演唱的《棒棒糖》
I got some Winstons.
我带了香烟
Hocked them off my old man's dresser.
从我老爸的柜子偷拿的
One apiece, for after supper.
吃完晚餐抽一根
That's cool.
- 很好 - 对
That's when a cigarette tastes best, after supper.
吃完晚餐抽的烟最棒了
Right.
对
Do you think I'm weird?
你觉得我很怪吗？
-Definitely. -No, seriously.
- 怪死了 - 认真回答
Am I weird?
我很怪吗？
Yes, but so what? Everybody's weird.
怪又怎样？大家都怪呀
You ready for school?
你准备好开学了没？
Junior high.
国中了
You know what that means.
你知道这代表什么
By next June we'll all be split up.
明年六月我们就会分开
What are you talking about? Why would that happen?
你在说什么？怎么可能会发生？
'Cause it's not going to be like grammar school, that's why.
因为不会像小学的时候那样了
You'll be taking college courses, and me, Teddy, Vern we'll all be...
你会去上升学班 我 泰迪和维恩
...in the shop courses making ashtrays and birdhouses.
学怎么做烟灰缸和鸟屋
You're gonna meet a lot of new guys. Smart guys.
你会遇到很多聪明的新朋友
-Meet a lot of pussies is what you mean. -No, man.
- 你是说遇到很多娘儿们 - 不是
Don't say that. Don't even think that.
别这样说 也别这样想
-I'm not going in with a lot of pussies. -Then you're an asshole.
- 我不会跟那种娘们做朋友 - 那你就是混蛋
What's asshole with wanting to be with your friends?
想跟朋友在一起算什么混蛋？
It's asshole if your friends drag you down.
你让朋友拖累你就是混蛋
You hang with us, you'll just be another wise guy with shit for brains.
你跟我们混 就会变成笨蛋
You think Mighty Mouse could beat up Superman?
你觉得太空飞鼠打得过超人吗？
-What are you, cracked? -Why not?
- 你吃错药了吗？ - 为什么？
The other day, he was carrying five elephants in one hand.
我那天看到他一手托起五只大象
You don't know nothin'.
天啊 你真的什么都不懂
Mighty Mouse is a cartoon.
太空飞鼠是个卡通
Superman is a real guy. No way a cartoon could beat up a real guy.
超人是真的 卡通才不能打得过真人
Yeah, maybe you're right.
你说得也许是对的
Would be a good fight, though.
但应该实力相当
You could be a real writer someday.
你有一天可以成为真正的作家 高弟
Fuck writing! I don't to be a writer.
去他的作家 我才不想当
-It's stupid. It's a stupid waste of time. -That's your dad talking.
- 那很蠢 那是在浪费时间 - 那是你爸说的
-Bullshit!   -Bulltrue!
- 骗人 - 才没有!
I know how your dad feels about you. He doesn't care about you.
我知道你爸怎么对你 他根本不关心你
Denny was the one he cared about, and don't try to tell me different.
他只关心丹尼 你别想辩解
You're just a kid, Gordie.
你只是个孩子 高弟
Gee thanks, Dad.
谢喽 老爸
I wish to hell I was your dad.
我还真希望我是你爸
You wouldn't be talking about taking these stupid shop courses if I was.
这样你就不会说要跟我一样 去上专科学校
It's like God gave you something, man, all those stories that you can make up...
上天给了你一份礼物 你很会说故事
...and He said, "This is what we got for you. Try not to lose it."
他说: "我们给你的礼物 孩子 要好好珍惜"
Kids lose everything unless there's someone there to look out for them.
但除非有人替他看好 孩子是很容易丢掉礼物的
If your parents are too fucked-up to do it, then maybe I should.
假如你的父母无法照顾你 那只好由我来
Come on, you guys, let's get moving.
快点 动作快
By the time we get there the kid won't even be dead anymore.
等我们到了那里 那小孩都活过来了
Any of you guys know when the next train is due?
你们知道下一班列车几点过吗？
We could go down to the Route 136 Bridge.
我们可以走到136公路的桥
What? Are you crazy? That's five miles down the river.
你疯了吗？要沿着河走八公里耶
You walk five miles down the river, you gotta walk five miles back.
走八公里 再走回来
That could take till dark.
也许就天黑了
We go across here, we can get to the same place in 10 minutes.
我们从这里过 可以十分钟内到达一样的地方
But if a train comes, there's nowhere to go.
对 但要是火车来了 就没地方闪
No, there isn't. You just jump.
没地方就跳呀
-Teddy, it's a 100 feet. -Yeah, Teddy.
- 泰迪 这高度有三十公尺 - 对 泰迪
You guys can go around if you want.
你们要绕远路就去吧
I'm crossing here.
我要从这里过
And while you guys are dragging your candyasses...
当你们拖着懦弱的身子
...half-way across the state and back, I'll be waiting for you on the other side...
走了将近半个州的路程 我早就在另一边
...relaxing with my thoughts.
轻松地等着你们了
You use your left hand or your right hand for that?
你是用左手还右手打手枪的？
You wish.
不告诉你
I lost the comb.
梳子掉了
Forget it, Vern.
算了 维恩
Train!
火车!
Shit!
完了!
Move it, man! Go on! Move it!
快起来! 快跑!
Get up, Vern! Damn it!
快起来! 维恩 该死!
Get up! Move it!
快起来! 快!
Shit, Vern!
惨了! 维恩!
-Get up, man! -I don't want to. We're gonna fall.
- 快起来呀!  - 我不想起来 会掉下去的
We're gonna die, damn it! Get up!
我们会被撞死 快起来!
Go.
快
-You've got to go faster! -I can't, Gordie!
- 维恩 跑快点!  - 我跑不动了 高弟!
Run!
快跑!
Run, Vern, run! Move your ass!
跑 快跑 动作快点
Run, goddamn it, run!
快跑 该死 跑!
At least now we know when the next train was due.
至少我们现在知道 下班列车什么时候到
That was the all-time train dodge. Too cool.
刚才的闪火车真是经典 太酷了
You were so scared you looked like Abbott Costello when he saw the mummy.
你怕得要死 就像电影里看见木乃伊落荒而逃的胖子
I wasn't that scared.
我才没那么怕
No, really, I wasn't. Sincerely.
真的没有
Then you won't mind if we check your underpants for Hershey squirts.
好 那你可以脱裤子让我们看你有没有便便？
Go screw.
去死啦
You'd better turn yours over.
维恩 赶快翻面
This is the way I like to do it.
我喜欢吃熟一点的
Man!
喔 天啊!
You got any more, Gordie?
高弟 你还有多出来的肉吗？
Sorry, Vern.
抱歉 维恩
It's not funny. What am I supposed to eat?
真是的 这样我要吃什么？
-Why don't you cook your dick? -It'd be a small meal.
- 烤你自己的鸡鸡呀 - 真小的一餐
Screw you guys, I got it.
去你们的 我搞定了
Nothing like a smoke after a meal.
饭后一根烟 快乐似神仙
I cherish these moments.
对 我很珍惜这种时候
What? What did I say?
怎么了 我说错了吗？
Gordie, why don't you tell us a story?
高弟 跟我们说个故事吧？
I don't know.
不好吧
-Come on. -Yeah, come on, Gordie.
- 拜托嘛 - 对呀 高弟
None of your horror stories, okay?
但不要说鬼故事 好吗？
I don't want to hear no horror stories. I'm not up for that.
我不想听什么鬼故事 没心情听
Tell us one about Sergeant Steel and his battling leathernecks.
跟我们说铁中士大战海军的故事吧？
The one I've been thinking about is kind of different.
我在构想的故事有点不同
It's about this pie-eating contest.
是关于比赛吃派的故事
The main guy of the story is this fat kid that nobody likes, named Davie Hogan.
故事的主角是个大家都讨厌的胖小孩 戴维•荷根
Like Charlie Hogan's brother, if he had one.
假如查理•荷根有弟弟 就是他了
Good, Vern.
好 维恩
Go on.
继续说 高弟
Well, this kid, he's our age, but he's fat. Real fat.
这个小孩跟我们一样大 但他很胖 非常胖
He weighs close to 180, but it's not his fault. It's his glands.
他大概80几公斤 但这不是他的错 他内分泌失调
My cousin's like that. Sincerely.
我表妹也是这样 真的
She weighs over 300 pounds. Supposed to be a "hyboid" gland or somethin'.
她130几公斤 好像是什么"甲状腺"的分泌失调
I don't know about any "hyboid" gland, but what a blimp!
我不懂什么"甲状腺" 但她真的超胖
No shit. She looks like a Thanksgiving turkey.
没骗你们 就像感恩节的大火鸡
-And, you know, this one time... -Shut up, Vern.
- 有一次… - 闭嘴好吗 维恩？
Right. Go on. It's a swell story.
好 继续说 高弟 很棒的故事
All the kids, instead of calling him Davie, they called him Lardass. Lardass Hogan.
所有的人不是叫他戴维 而是叫他肥猪 肥猪荷根
Even his little brother and sister called him Lardass.
甚至他的弟弟妹妹都叫他肥猪
At school they put this sticker on his back that says, "Wide Load."
他在学校被贴"超重载货"的标签在背上
And they rank him out and beat him up whenever they get a chance.
他们逮到机会就侮辱他 打他
But one day he gets an idea.
但有一天他想到了一个主意
The greatest revenge idea a kid ever had.
是一个小孩想出来 最伟大的复仇计划
Is this thing on? Can you hear me?
麦克风开了吗？听得见吗？
The next contestant in the Great Tri-County Pie Eat...
下一位参加三区联合大胃王吃派比赛的
...Principal John Wiggins.
是约翰•威根斯校长
三区联合大胃王吃派比赛
And our celebrity contestant, from KLAM in Portland...
还有名人参赛者 波特兰KLAM电台的
...The Boss-man himself, Bob Cormier!
大老板鲍伯•寇米耶
谢谢主持人
From the racks and stacks it"s the best on wax...
男女老少 东南西北
...how about another double, golden oldie, sound sandwich from KLAM in Portland...
吉祥如意 招财进宝 波特兰KLAM电台
- it's... - Boss!
- 我是… - 大老板
Next, a newcomer to the Pie Eat, but one we expect...
接下来的参赛者是新人
...great things from in the future, young Master David Hogan.
但前途一片光明 欢迎戴维•荷根小朋友
-Are you all right, young man? -Lardass how was your trip?
- 你还好吗？小朋友 - 喂 肥猪 摔得好吗？
I hear you got a big appetite, Lardass.
我听说你的胃口不小 肥猪
Don't even think about winning this.
别想要赢得比赛
Boy are you fat.
你还真肥
Don't pay attention to those fools, Lardass. Davie.
别理他们 肥猪 我是说 戴维
And now, the one you"ve all been waiting for.
现在要介绍的是众所期待
The four-time champion, our own Bill Travis.
连续四届的冠军 比尔•崔维斯
Listen I got $10 riding on you myself, Billy Boy.
比尔 我下了十块钱赌注在你身上
All right. Are you ready?
好 大家准备好了吗？
Hands behind your backs, gentlemen.
手放背后 各位
Drum roll.
鼓声
Hey, Lardass. Chow down, Wide Load.
肥猪 吞快点 超重载货
Go.
开始
Done!
吃完了
You better pace yourself, if you want to hold out.
假如你想持久 要控制速度
Come on, Lardass!
加油 肥猪
Lardass, Lardass!
- 肥猪  - 肥猪
What the audience didn't know, was that Lardass wasn't interested in winning.
观众所不知道的 是肥猪志不在赢得比赛
What he wanted was revenge.
而是在复仇
And right before he was introduced, he'd gotten ready for it.
在他被介绍上台前 他就已经准备好了
...Principal John Wiggins.
约翰•威根斯校长
篦麻油
And our celebrity contestant from KLAM in Portland...
还有名人参赛者 波特兰KLAM电台的
...The Bossman himself, Bob Cormier!
大老板鲍伯•寇米耶
From the racks and stacks it"s the best on wax...
男女老少 东南西北
...how about another double, golden oldie, sound sandwich from KLAM in Portland...
吉祥如意 招财进宝 波特兰KLAM电台
it's....
我是…
Done.
吃完了
Diving into his fifth pie, Lardass began to imagine that he wasn"t eating pies.
肥猪吃到第五个派时 开始想像他不是在吃派
He pretended he was eating cowflops...
而是在吃沾满蓝莓酱的
...and rat guts in blueberry sauce.
牛粪和老鼠内脏
Done.
吃完了
Slowly, a sound started to build in Lardass"s stomach.
渐渐地 从肥猪的胃里 传来一阵声音
A strange and scary sound...
奇怪又可怕的声音
...like a log truck coming atyou at 100 miles an hour.
好像载满伐木的卡车 以一百多公里的时速迎面冲来
Suddenly, Lardass opened his mouth...
突然 肥猪张开了嘴巴
...and before Bill Travis knew it...
比尔•崔维斯还没警觉
...he was covered with five pies worth of used blueberries.
就被吐出来的五个蓝莓派 弄得满身都是
The women in the audience screamed.
观众席的女士开始尖叫
Bossman Bob Cormier took one look at Bill Travis and barfed on Wiggins.
大老板鲍伯•寇米耶看了比尔一眼 就吐在威根斯校长身上
Wiggins barfed on the lumberjack that was sitting next to him.
威根斯校长吐在隔壁的伐木工人身上
Mayor Grundy barfed on his wife"s tits!
格兰迪市长吐在他老婆的胸部上
But when the smell hit the crowd...
一旦呕吐的恶臭传到了观众席
...that's when Lardass's plan really started to work.
肥猪的计划就开始生效了
Girlfriends barfed on boyfriends.
女孩子吐在男友身上
Kids barfed on theirparents.
小孩吐在爸妈身上
A fatlady barfed in herpurse.
有个胖女士吐在包包里
The Donelley twins barfed on each other.
唐利双胞胎互吐在身上
The Women"s Auxiliary barfed all over the Benevolent Order ofAntelopes.
妇女团体全部都吐在羚羊会的会员身上
And Lardass just sat back and enjoyed what he'd created.
肥猪坐在椅子上 开心地欣赏他的杰作
A complete and total barfarama.
呕吐接力大赛
-Too cool! -That was the best, just the best.
- 太酷了! 太酷了!  - 这故事真棒
Then what happened?
然后呢？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I mean, what happened?
我是说 后来呢？
What do you mean, "What happened?" That's the end.
什么"后来"？故事结束了
How can that be the end? What kind of an ending is that? What happens to Lardass?
那怎么可能是结局？那是什么结局？肥猪后来怎么了？
I don't know.
不知道
Maybe he went home and celebrated with a couple of cheeseburgers.
也许他回家吃起士汉堡庆祝
Jesus, that ending sucks.
好烂的结局喔
Why don't you make it so that Lardass goes home...
你可以让肥猪回家
...and he shoots his father.
然后开枪杀死他爸
Then he runs away and he joins the Texas Rangers.
然后他逃家 加入德州游骑兵队
How about that?
怎么样？
I don't know.
不好吧
Something good like that.
类似这样的结局
I like the ending. The barfing was good.
我喜欢本来的结局 呕吐大赛很好
But there's one thing I didn't understand.
但有一件事我不懂
Did Lardass have to pay to get into the contest?
肥猪参加比赛要付钱吗？
No, Vern, they just let him in.
不用 他们免费让他参加
Great, great story.
喔 那这个故事太好了
It's a great story. I just didn't like the ending.
对呀 很棒的故事 高弟 我只是不喜欢它的结局
Where's the radio? Let's see if we can get some sounds.
维恩 收音机在哪？看看能不能接收到声音
Here.
在这里
We talked into the night.
我们一直聊到深夜
The kind of talk thatseemed important until you discover girls.
聊些在还没对女生产生兴趣前 都觉得很重要的话题
All right.
好 很好
Mickey's a Mouse. Donald's a duck. Pluto's a dog.
米奇是老鼠 唐老鸭是鸭子 布鲁多是狗
What's Goofy?
那高飞呢？
If I could only have one food for the rest of my life?
假如我这辈子只能吃一种东西？
That's easy. Pez.
简单 一定是佩兹糖
Cherry flavoured Pez. No question about it.
樱桃口味的 还用说吗
Goofy's a dog. He's definitely a dog.
高飞是一只狗 一定是
I knew the $64,000 Question was fixed.
我知道The $64,000 Question 益智节目都是做假的
There's no way anybody can know that much about opera.
不可能有人这么了解歌剧
He can't be a dog. He wears a hat and drives a car.
他应该不是狗 他戴帽子还会开车
Wagon Train is a really cool show...
《马车队》很好看
...but did you ever notice that they never get anywhere?
但你们有没有注意到他们都开不到目的地？
They just keep wagon training.
他们只是一直坐车
God, that's weird.
真奇怪
What the hell is Goofy?
高飞到底是啥东西？
Not one of us mentioned Ray Brower, but we were all thinking about him.
我们都没有提到雷•布洛尔 虽然心里都在想着他
Oh, my God.
天啊
It's the Brower kid.
是那个布洛尔的声音
His ghost is out walking in the woods.
他的鬼魂在森林走动
I promise I won't hock no more dirty books.
我发誓我不会再看黄色书刊了
I promise I won't say no more bad swears. I promise I'll eat my lima beans.
我发誓我不会再骂脏话 而且会吃光豆子
Two for flinching.
缩一下打两下
What is it, Chris?
怎么了 克里斯？
Maybe it's coyotes.
可能是土狼
Sounds like a woman screaming.
听起来好像女人在叫
It's not coyotes. It's his ghost.
不是土狼 是他的鬼魂
Don't say that.
别说了
Teddy, sit down.
泰迪 坐下
I'm gonna go look for it. I want to see the ghost.
我要去找他 我想看鬼魂
Don't say that.
别说了
I just want to see it! I just want to see what he looks like.
我只想去看看他长什么样子
Jesus H. Bald-headed Christ!
我的老天爷啊!
Maybe we should stand guard.
也许我们应该轮流站岗
That's a good idea.
好主意
Give me the gun. I'll take the first watch.
给我手枪 我先站
23:00 hours. Corporal Teddy Duchamp stands guard.
晚上11点 泰迪•杜相下士站岗
No sign of the enemy. The fort is secure.
没有敌人迹象 堡垒安全
Shut up, Teddy, and keep your eyes peeled.
闭嘴 泰迪 眼睛睁大点
-Cut it out. -I'm trying to sleep.
- 泰迪 别闹了 - 我想睡觉
The dogfaces rested easy...
所有的官兵
...in the knowledge that Corporal Teddy Duchamp...
都因为知道他们所爱的一切有泰迪•杜相下士保护
...was protecting all that was dear to them.
而睡得甘甜
Itshould have been you, Gordon.
死的人应该是你 高弟
Are you okay?
你还好吧？
You were dreaming.
你做梦了
I didn't cry at Denny's funeral.
我在丹尼的丧礼上都没有哭
I miss him, Chris.
我好想他 克里斯
I really miss him.
我真的好想他
I know.
我知道
Go back to sleep.
快睡吧
Maybe you could go into the college courses with me.
你也许可以跟我一起上升学班
That'll be the day.
不太可能
Why not? You're smart enough.
为什么？你很聪明
They won't let me.
他们不会让我去的
What do you mean?
什么意思？
It's the way the people think of my family in this town.
这个城镇的人就是这样看我的家庭
It's the way they think of me. I'm just one of those low-life Chambers kids.
他们就是这样看我 我只是卑贱的钱伯斯家的一分子
That's not true.
才怪
It is.
真的
No one asked me if I took the milk money.
没有人问我牛奶钱是不是我拿的
I just got a three-day vacation.
就把我停学三天
Did you take it?
是你拿的吗？
Yeah, I took it. You knew I took it.
对 你知道是我拿的
Teddy knew I took it.
泰迪也知道
Everyone knew I took it. Even Vern knew, I think.
大家都知道是我拿的 甚至连维恩都知道
Maybe I was sorry, and I tried to give it back.
也许我很歉疚 然后还回去了
You tried to give it back?
你还回去了？
Maybe, just maybe.
也许是这样
Maybe I took it to Old Lady Simons and told her, and the money was all there.
也许我拿去西蒙斯老师那里 跟她坦白 牛奶钱都在那
But I still got a three-day vacation, because it never showed up.
但我还是被停学三天 因为牛奶钱一直没找到
And maybe the next week, old Lady Simons...
也许下个星期 西蒙斯老师
...had this brand new skirt on when she came to school.
穿着一件全新的裙子去上课
Yeah, it was brown and it had dots on it.
对 咖啡色有点点的裙子
Let's just say that I stole the milk money, but old Lady Simons stole it back from me.
所以也许我偷了牛奶钱 但西蒙斯老师把它偷回去了
Just suppose that I told this story.
假如我说了这个事情
Me, Chris Chambers, kid brother to Eyeball Chambers.
我 克里斯•钱伯斯 眼球钱伯斯的弟弟
Do you think anyone would have believed it?
你觉得有人会相信我吗？
No.
没有
You think that bitch would have tried that if it had been one of those douche bags...
你觉得假如是那些住在高级住宅区的人偷的钱
...from The View, if they had taken the money?
那个贱人会这样处理吗？
-No way. -Hell, no.
- 不可能 - 当然
But, with me....
但换做是我…
I'm sure she had her eye on that skirt for a long time.
我敢说她一定看那件裙子看了很久
Anyway, she saw her chance and she took it.
机会一来 她就拿了钱
I was the stupid one for even trying to give it back.
我还笨到把钱归还
I just never thought....
我只是没想到
I never thought that a teacher....
我没想过一个老师…
Who gives a fuck anyway?
谁在乎这种鸟事？
I just wish...
我只希望
...that I could go someplace where nobody knows me.
我可以去一个没有人认识我的地方
I guess I'm just a pussy.
我只不过是个娘们
No way, man.
你不是
《帮派风云》
The freight woke up the other guys...
运货的火车吵醒了大家
...and it was on the tip of my tongue to tell them about the deer, but I didn"t.
我一直很想说出看见鹿的事 但一直没说
That was the one thing I kept to myself.
那成为我唯一的秘密
I"ve neverspoken or written ofit untiljust now.
我直到现在才说出来 写出来
How come you didn't get some breakfast stuff like...
高弟 你怎么没买早餐要吃的
...Twinkies, and Pez, and root beer?
例如糖果 佩兹糖和麦根沙士？
Sorry. I guess a more experienced shopper could've gotten more for your 7 cents.
抱歉 更有经验的购物专家应该可以更好地利用你的七分钱
With ourstomachs rumbling, we pressed on toward the Royal River.
我们饿着肚子 往皇家河走去
The reality of Ray Brower was growing, and kept us moving despite the heat.
雷•布洛尔就在眼前 成了我们在大热天奔走的动力
For me, the idea ofseeing that kid"s dead body...
对我来说 要看见那个小孩的尸体
...was starting to become an obsession.
已经成了一种执迷
Gentlemen, the Royal.
各位 皇家河到了
God, the tracks go way out of the way.
天啊 铁轨往那边走
We cut across this field right here, we'll be there in an hour.
假如我们穿过林野 一小时内就会到了
I think we should stick to the tracks.
我觉得应该要沿着铁路走
I say we go across the field.
我们穿过森林吧
Gordie?
高弟 你说呢？
-Yeah. -Let's go.
- 好 - 走吧
Take no prisoners!
赶尽杀绝
You guys, it's a lot safer if we....
我觉得还是走铁轨比较安全…
Come on, men. Let's take on the....
大家听我说 走铁轨…
You don't know what's in those woods.
我们又不知道树林里有什么
You guys, wait up for me!
等等我呀
I gotta tell you something, but swear on your mother's name...
老大 我有事告诉你 你以你妈妈的名声发誓
...that you won't tell anybody.
绝不会告诉任何人
You got it, pal.
没问题 老兄
Eyeball, you know that Brower kid?
眼球 你知道那个叫布洛尔的小孩吗？
What about him?
他怎么了？
I'll tell you something, but you must swear on your mother's good name...
我告诉你一件事 但你要以你妈妈的好名声来发誓
...you won't tell nobody.
你不会告诉任何人
Billy and Charlie had managed to keep their enormous secret for about 36 hours.
比利和查理忍住天大的秘密 也不过36小时
A personal record for both of them.
对他们来说已经是破纪录了
By noon, Ace and Eyeball had told theirsecret to everybody in the gang.
中午以前 老大和眼球 就已经将秘密传给帮派里所有的弟兄了
I guess for those guys, protecting their mother"s good name wasn"t a top priority.
对他们来说 保护妈妈的好名声 一点也不重要
Ace, maybe me and Charlie shouldn't go.
老大 也许我和查理不应该去
Maybe you could go without us?
对 你们去就好了
You guys are acting like my grandmother having a conniption fit.
你们的行为好像老太婆的情绪反应
I don't see your problem.
你们有什么问题
We take a bunch of fishing gear, so if a cop asks us what we're doing:
假如条子问我们在那里干嘛 我们一大群人带着钓具去
"We're here to take a couple of steelhead out of the river. Look what we found."
"我们去河里钓鱼 结果看我们找到了什么"
Come on, man, we're gonna be famous.
对呀 我们会成名的
We'll be on every radio and TV show in the country.
我们会上遍各大电台和电视节目
I still don't think we should go.
我还是认为我们不该去
Okay.
好
You've stated your position clearly.
你们说得很清楚了
Now, I'm gonna state mine.
换我说了
Get in the fucking car. Now!
快给我滚上车!
Let's go, man.
- 走吧 - 对 走
-I hate this shortcut. -"I hate this shortcut."
- 我讨厌这个捷径 - "我讨厌这个捷径"
You flinched! Two for flinching.
你退缩了! 缩一下打两下
But you flinched.
但你退缩了
I know. Two for flinching.
我知道啊 缩一下打两下嘛
How are we supposed to get across this?
我们怎么过得了？
-We use you as a raft. -Very funny.
- 用你当划桨 - 真好笑
It's not that deep. We can walk across.
水根本不深 走过去就好
I told you we should have stuck to the tracks.
我就说应该沿着铁轨走
Is it me, or are you the world's biggest pussy?
你是全世界最娘的娘们
I suppose this is fun for you.
你觉得很好笑吗？
No, but this is.
不 但这还蛮好笑的
Want some more?
要再来一点吗？
-Stop it, come on! -Act your age.
- 住手 别闹了!  - 泰迪 成熟一点
This is my age.
我很成熟啊
I'm in the prime of my youth, and I'll only be young once.
我是青少年的黄金时期 人生只能年轻一次
But you're going to be stupid for the rest of your life.
对 但你接下来会愚蠢一辈子
That's it, Chambers. You just signed your own death warrant.
好了 钱伯斯 这是你自找的
You die, Chambers!
去死吧 钱伯斯!
Get him, Chambers!
抓住他! 抓住维恩!
-Vern's afraid he's gonna die! -Teddy, you're gonna die!
- 维恩•塔西欧去死   - 不 泰迪 你才去死
Where do you think you're going, Lachance?
拉强斯 你想去哪里？
Come on, you guys.
大家过来吧
Pile on!
叠上去!
I don't want to do this.
- 别这样 我不想玩 - 快叠上去
Get off!
走开!
-Sleeper hold. -Stop it. I'm serious.
- 摔角招式固定法 - 别闹了 我说真的
No one gets out of the sleeper hold.
没有人能脱逃
-Vern, there's something on your neck. -I'm not falling for that one, Lachance.
- 维恩 你脖子上有东西 - 少来了 我才不会相信
No, there is something on your neck.
不 维恩 真的有东西在你脖子上
It's a leech. Leeches!
是血蛭! 血蛭!
-Oh, my God! -Leeches!
- 天啊!  - 血蛭!
Get them off!
快拍下来!
Lay off me!
它们爬满我全身!
-Gordie, there's some on your back. -Get them off!
- 高弟 你背上也有 - 快拍掉!
Are there any on mine?
我的背有吗？
Oh, shit, Chris.
完了 克里斯
Oh, shit, man.
完了
Are you okay?
高弟 你没事吗？
Can you hear me?
你听得见吗？
Are you there?
高弟 你还好吗？
Maybe he's dead.
也许他死了
He's not dead. He's still breathing, idiot.
他没死 他还在呼吸 白痴
I don't know.
我不知道
Just cool it, you guys. He just fainted.
没事 他只是晕倒了
I never met anybody who fainted before.
天啊 我从来没看过别人晕倒
Maybe he made a bad mistake and looked at your face.
也许他不应该看你的脸
Shut up, Teddy.
闭嘴 泰迪
You okay?
没事吧？高弟
-Yeah. -Let's go.
- 没事 - 走吧
Maybe we should take Gordie back.
也许我们应该送高弟回家
Great, Chambers, now you're turning pussy, too!
太好了 钱伯斯 你也变成娘们了!
What's your problem? He had a leech on his balls. He fainted.
他的蛋蛋上有只血蛭 所以晕倒了
Are you his mother?
你是他妈妈吗？
-Eat shit. -You eat shit.
- 去吃屎 - 你才去吃屎
I think Chris is right. Let's go back.
克里斯说得对 我们回去吧
What a surprise! The king of the pussies wants to go back, too.
真令人意外 娘们的王后也想回家了
-Stop calling me that. -What, "pussy"? Pussy!
- 别叫我娘们 - 怎样？"娘们" 娘们!
-Stop it! -Pussy!
- 闭嘴!  - 娘们
You four-eyed psycho!
你这个四眼疯子
Get off me!
放开我
Two for flinching. Do I get two for flinching?
缩一下打两下 你喜欢吗？
- Stop it!  - You like it, Teddy?
- 住手 - 你喜欢喔 泰迪？
-Come on, you guys. Break it up. -Stop it!
- 好了 别闹了 - 停 住手
I'm not going back.
我不回去
-Idiot. -Shut up! Retard.
- 白痴 - 闭嘴 笨蛋
At the time, I didn"t know why I needed to see that body so badly.
在当时 我不知道为何我那么想看尸体
Even if no one had followed me, I would have gone on alone.
甚至没有人跟我去的话 我也会一个人前往
No way, Ace! Not this time, man. No way!
不 老大! 这次不会输给你!
-Go for it, Vince. -You want to race?
- 加油 文斯 加油 - 你想赛车 好呀？
Oh, my God, I got him.
我的天啊 我赢了
You are history. History!
你真是输惨了 小子
-Fall back, Ace. -Don't fuck around.
- 住手 老大 - 别开玩笑
Jesus Christ, Ace! Fall back, man!
- 天啊 快闪开 老大!  - 你在做什么？
Shit, man! Shit!
妈的! 完了!
I won.
我赢了
You let him beat you, you cock-knocker.
你让他赢了 娘炮
Coming though the woods, I bet we saved over an hour.
我们穿过森林捷径 应该节省了一小时
Is this the Back Harlow Road?
这就是后哈洛路吗？
The Brower kid must be around here someplace.
布洛尔一定就在附近
Teddy and Vern watch the left side of the tracks.
泰迪 你和维恩看路的左边
-We'll take the right. -All right.
- 我们看右边 - 好
There he is! I see him! Look!
他在那里! 我看到了! 你们看!
Look over there! I see him!
看那里! 我看到他了
None of us could breathe.
没有人能呼吸
Somewhere under those bushes was the rest of Ray Brower.
躺在树丛下的就是雷•布洛尔
The train had knocked Ray out of his Keds...
火车撞得他鞋子都飞了
...justlike it had knocked the life out of his body.
就像把他的魂都撞飞了一样
Jesus.
天啊
The kid wasn"tsick.
这孩子没有生病
The kid wasn"tsleeping.
这孩子不是在睡觉
The kid was dead.
他死了
Let's look for some long branches. We'll build him a stretcher.
我们去找一些树枝来当担架
Gordie?
高弟？
Why did you have to die?
你为什么要死？
What's the matter with Gordie?
高弟怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
You guys just go over there and look for some branches?
你去那边找树枝
Okay.
好
Why did he have to die, Chris?
他为什么要死 克里斯？
Why did Denny have to die? Why?
他为什么要死？为什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
-It should have been me. -Don't say that.
- 死的人应该是我 - 别说这种话
-It should have been me. -Don't say that, man.
- 应该是我死才对 - 别这样说
I'm no good. My dad said it. I'm no good.
我是坏小孩 我爸说我是坏孩子
He doesn't know you.
他不懂你
He hates me.
他恨我
He doesn't hate you.
他是不懂你
-He hates me. -No.
- 他恨我 - 不
He just doesn't know you.
他只是不懂你
He hates me. My dad hates me.
他恨我 我爸爸恨我
He hates me. Oh, God.
他恨我 天啊
You're gonna be a great writer someday.
你有一天会成为伟大的作家 高弟
You might even write about us guys, if you ever get hard-up for material.
你有一天没灵感的时候 或许还会写我们的故事
I guess I'd have to be pretty hard-up?
那还真的走投无路了喔？
Yeah.
对
What the fuck do you know about this?
你们知道什么？
Son of a bitch! My little brother.
妈的 是我弟
You wasn't planning on taking the body from us, was you, boys?
你们没打算要把尸体搬走吧？
You get away.
走开 老兄
We found him. We got dibs.
先找到的人有权利
We better start running, Eyeball. They got dibs.
我们最好快跑 眼球 他们有权利耶
We earned him. You guys came in a car. That's not fair. He's ours.
他是我们努力得来的 你们开车来的 不公平 他是我们的
"That's not fair. He's ours."
"不公平 他是我们的"
Well, not anymore.
他现在是我们的了
There are four of us, Eyeball. You just make your move.
我们有四个人 眼球 你尽管来呀
We will. Don't you worry.
我们会动手的 别担心
Vern, you little son of a whore.
维恩 你这小贼头
-You was under the porch. -No, I swear it wasn't me.
- 你躲在阳台下 - 我发誓不是我
You keyhole-peeping bung. I ought to beat the living shit out of you.
你这贼头贼脑的偷听鬼 看我怎么打死你
You guys have two choices.
你们有两个选择
Either leave quietly and we take the body...
安静地离开 把尸体留给我们
...or you stay and we beat the shit out of you.
或留下来被我们打死
And we take the body.
然后我们拿走尸体
-Besides, me and Billy found him first. -Vern told us how you found him.
- 再说 是我和比利先找到的 - 对 维恩说过你们怎么找到的
"Billy, I wish we'd never boosted that car."
"比利 我希望我们没有偷车"
"Billy, I think I just turned my Fruit of the Looms into fudge factory."
"比利 我好像刚刚大便在裤子里了"
-That's it. Your ass is grass! -Hold it.
- 够了 你完蛋了!  - 等一下
Okay, Chambers, you little faggot. This is your last chance.
好 钱伯斯 你这小娘们 这是你最后的机会
What do you say, kid?
你怎么说 小鬼？
Why don't you go home and fuck your mother some more?
你们回家去跟妈妈上床吧!
You're dead.
你死定了
Come on, let's split.
克里斯 我们走吧
-They're not taking him. -Come on, this is crazy.
- 他们不能带走他 - 好了 这太疯狂了
-They're not taking him. -He's got a knife, man.
- 他们不能带走他 - 他手上有刀
Ace, come on.
老大 别闹了
You're gonna have to kill me, Ace.
你得杀了我 老大
No problem.
没问题
You're not taking him. Nobody's taking him.
你不能带他走 谁都不能
Come on, kid, just give me the gun before you take your foot off.
小鬼 在你射到自己的脚以前 把枪给我
You ain't got the sack to shoot a woodchuck.
你连开枪射小鸟的胆子都没有
Don't move, Ace.
别动 老大
I'll kill you. I swear to God.
我会杀了你 我发誓
Come on, Lachance, give me the gun.
拉强斯 把枪给我
You must have at least some of your brother's good sense.
你应该跟你哥一样聪明
Suck my fat one, you cheap dime-store hood.
滚下地狱吧 你这个小偷
What are you going to do, shoot us all?
你要怎么办？杀光我们吗？
No, just you.
不 我只杀你一个
We're gonna get you for this.
我们会讨回来的
Maybe you will and maybe you won't.
讨不讨都无所谓
We will.
我们会报仇的
We're not going to forget this, if that's what you're thinking.
我们不会忘记的
This is big time, baby.
事情大条了
"Suck my fat one"?
"滚下地狱"?
Whoever told you, you had a fat one, Lachance?
谁跟你说地狱是用滚下去的？
Biggest one in four counties.
大家都这么说
Are we going to take him?
我们要带他走吗？
No.
不
But we came all this way?
但我们走了这么远耶
We're supposed to be heroes.
我们应该当英雄的
Not this way, Teddy.
不是这边 泰迪
Chris, give me a hand.
帮我一下 克里斯
Ray Brower"s body was found...
雷•布洛尔的尸体被找到了
...but neither our gang nor their gang got the credit.
但没有人去邀功
We decided that an anonymous phone call was the best thing to do.
到最后 我们决定匿名报警是最好的选择
We headed home. And although many thoughts raced through our minds...
我们回家了 虽然路上有许多想法
...we barely spoke.
但我们几乎都没说话
We walked all night and made it back to Castle Rock...
我们彻夜走回凯斯罗
...a little past 5:00 on Sunday morning, the day before Labour Day.
劳工节前一天的星期天早上五点多到达
We"d only been gone two days, butsomehow the town seemed different...
我们只有离开两天 城镇看起来有些不同
...smaller.
它变小了
See you in school.
学校见
- Yeah!    - Yeah!
- 好 - 好
See you in Junior High.
国中见
Penny.
一分钱耶
I better get home, before my mom puts me on the "10 Most Wanted List."
在我老妈报"十大悬赏名单"以前 我最好赶快回家
No hard feelings, okay?
别生气 好吗？
No way, man.
不会
As time went on we saw less and less of Teddy and Vern...
渐渐地 我们就越来越少看见泰迪和维恩
...until eventually they became just two more faces in the halls.
直到友情淡化成仅止于点头之交
It happens sometimes.
有时候会有这种事
Friends come in and out ofyourlife like busboys in a restaurant.
朋友有时候就像过客
I heard that Vern got married out of high school, had four kids...
我听说维恩高中毕业后结了婚 生了四个孩子
...and is now the forklift operator at the Arsenault Lumber Yard.
现在在亚斯诺伐木场开起重机
Teddy tried to getinto the Army, but his eyes and his ear kept him out.
泰迪多次报考军队 但他的近视和耳疾让他不及格
Last l"d heard he"d spentsome time in jail...
最后我听说他坐了几年牢
...and was now doing oddjobs around Castle Rock.
然后在凯斯罗到处打工
I'm never gonna get out of this town, am l, Gordie?
我永远也出不了凯斯罗了 对吧 高弟？
You can do anything you want, man.
你想做什么都能做到
Sure.
才怪
Give me some skin.
握个手
I'll see you.
再见罗
Not if I see you first.
再见
Chris did get out.
克里斯离开了小镇
He enrolled in the college courses with me.
他跟我一起报名升学班
And although it was hard, he gutted it outlike he always did.
虽然很艰难 但他依旧咬着牙完成了
He went on to college and eventually became a lawyer.
之后上大学 最后成为律师
Last week, he entered a fast-food restaurant.
上个星期 他到速食餐厅
Just ahead of him, two men gotinto an argument.
在他前面有两个人在吵架
One of them pulled a knife.
其中一人拔出刀
Chris, who"d always made the bestpeace, tried to break it up.
克里斯一向行侠仗义 上前劝架
He was stabbed in the throat.
结果被一刀插进喉咙
He died almostinstantly.
几乎当场死亡
他被刀刺入喉咙 几乎当场死亡
虽然我已经十年没见到他了
但我会永远怀念他
爸 可以出发了吗？
- 你们准备好了吗？ - 一小时前就好了
好 我马上到
他半小前就说过这句话了
对 我爸很奇怪 他只要一写作就会这样
我再也没有交过像我12岁时那样的好朋友了
大家不都是这样吗？